Beryl Baldwin

LinkedIn

Social-impact-focused startup founder turned software engineer with a passion for product development and the product life cycle. Experienced in developing and implementing adaptive solutions to complex business problems at every stage of development. Exceptional at empathetic communication, idea articulation, critical thinking, and problem solving.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology, Innovation & Entrepreneurship Certificate Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp

Duke University General Assembly

JavaScript, SQL, Angular, React, HTML, CSS, Python

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Founder, Product Manager

Oct. 2018 - Present

Caia | Durham, NC

- Executed every stage of product and business development from concept to launch and revenue generation: product roadmap and vision, prototype design/development, product/market fit, website design, market research (customer interviews, customer surveys, data analysis), go-to-market strategy, and product launch.
- Raised \$20,000 in grant funding during pre-seed round from several highly competitive foundations.
- Exceeded revenue goals during launch by 60% with a strong go-to-market strategy and social media campaign.
- Collaborated with industry experts in oncology, women's health, materials, marketing, and business management to validate and deliver the strongest possible product to the market.
- Hired, directed, and collaborated with 4 employees, including a co-founder/CTO to strengthen all elements of the product life cycle.
- Orchestrated multiple social media campaigns that raised engagement by 1,018% and followers 179% over 30 days (not starting from 0).

Personal Assistant Jan. 2015 - Jan. 2017

Grammy-Nominated Artist | Los Angeles, CA

- Coordinated 1000+ engagements, ~75% of which required single-handedly aligning and communicating the objectives and timelines of 5+ separate teams.
- Supervised schedule, estate, staff, finances, correspondences, etc.
- Girl Friday to Artist in the music industry, providing 24/7 support, adaptive solutions to complex problems, and urgent task prioritization.
- Coordinated transportation, travel, wardrobe, and hair and makeup for Celebrity, 6 performers, and team.

Executive Assistant Oct. 2013 - Jan. 2015

Echo Lake Entertainment | Beverly Hills, CA

- Designed and created a comprehensive and interactive financial spreadsheet for 3 managers and their cumulative 112 clients, tracking client earnings, company revenue, and manager commission totaling more than \$8 million per year and increasing system efficiency by more than 65%.
- Organized and maintained extensive calendars and call sheets for 40 clients.
- Recruited, interviewed, trained, and oversaw 15 company interns.

SKILLS & LANGUAGES

Skills: Project & Product Management | Product Life Cycle | Product Roadmap | Organizational Strategy | Troubleshooting | User Research | Innovation | Leadership Experience | UX/UI Design | Google Analytics | Data Analysis | Agile Methodologies | Usability Testing | Javascript | CSS | HTML5 | Python | SQL | Angular | React **Languages:** German (conversational) | French (beginner)